Medbh McGuckian papers, 1964-2006
Emory University
- Writings by Medbh McGuckian, Series 2; Boxes 16-30, OP 1-3
  - Poetry, Subseries 2.1; Box 16 - Box 25: Folder 45; OP 1-3
    - "Reading in a Library," MS (Box 21a, Folder 45)
    - "Ring Worn Outside a Glove," MS (Box 21a, Folder 46)
    - "The Scissors Collection," MS (Box 21a, Folder 47)
    - "Scotch Argus on Jerusalem Sage," MS (Box 21a, Folder 48)
    - "The Sleep Cure," MS (Box 21a, Folder 49)
    - "The Sleeping Room," MS (Box 21a, Folder 50)
    - "Slieve Gallion," MS (Box 21a, Folder 51)
    - "To My Disordered Muse," MS (Box 21a, Folder 52)
    - "The Walking of the Land," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 53)
    - "Wet Birthday," MS (Box 21a, Folder 54)
    - "The Yellowest Child," MS (Box 21a, Folder 55)
    - The Book of the Angel (2004)
    - "The Angels Were a Mistake," MS (Box 21a, Folder 56)
    - "A Blessing Christ," MS (Box 21a, Folder 57)
    - "Cape Fear Bank," MS [variant title: "The Cape Fear Bank Garden"] (Box 21a, Folder 58)
    - "Celebration of the Name of St. Philomena," MS (Box 21a, Folder 59)
    - "Chairé," MS and TS (Box 21a, Folder 60)
    - "The Important Afterlife," MS (Box 21a, Folder 61)
    - "Modello," MS (Box 21a, Folder 62)
    - "My Carmelite Family," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Book of the Angel, "A Blessing Christ," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Poem Rhyming in J," MS (Box 21a, Folder 63)
    - "Poem Without Words," Notes, MS (Box 21a, Folder 64)
    - "Recipe for Red," MS (Box 21a, Folder 65)
    - "Sagrario," MS (Box 21a, Folder 66)
    - "Vision of a Soul's Release from Purgatory," MS (Box 21a, Folder 67)
    - The Book of the Angel, proof (Box 21a, Folder 68)
    - The Currach Requires No Harbours (2006) [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "Angel of the Countenance," Notes, MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Painting a Verb," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Anne Glyd, her Book, 1656," MS (Box 21a, Folder 69)
    - "Bright Star, I Say that Thou art Dust," proof (Box 21a, Folder 70)
    - "Colmo: Virgin of the Snow," MS (Box 21a, Folder 71)
    - "The Dependent Nature of Linen," MS (Box 21a, Folder 72)
    - "February House," Notes, MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Broca's Area," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Good Wife Taught her Daughter," MS (Box 21a, Folder 73)
    - "The Gorgon as Mistress of the Animals," MS (Box 21a, Folder 74)
    - "La Rosa de Santa Rosa," MS (Box 21a, Folder 75)
    - "Orant Figure," MS and proof [includes TLS, 20 July 2005, from Jaime Robles] (Box 21a, Folder 76)
    - "Regaining Control of the Night," MS (Box 21a, Folder 77)
    - "St. Gobnait Standing on a Beehive," MS (Box 21a, Folder 78)
    - "She Thinks She Sees Clarissa," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "The Gorgon as Mistress of the Animals," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "A Sovereign Medicine for the Greensickness," MS (Box 21a, Folder 79)
    - "Thorn Piece," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Painting a Verb," MS] (Box 21a, Folder 80)
    - "Three-legged Angel," MS (Box 21a, Folder 81)
    - "The Violet Maker," MS (Box 21a, Folder 82)
    - "Woman Forming the Handle of a Cane," MS (Box 21a, Folder 83)
    - Dust jacket text, TS (Box 21a, Folder 84)
    - Unpublished Collected Poems
    - The Butterfly Farm [includes "Stars," "Aunts," "Lychees," "That Year," "The Roofspace," "Cicely," "The Black Nun," "Inch," "The Sun Trap," "Choosing," "Fishing," "The Butterfly Farm," "Tupperware," "Dancing," "Truganini," "Thaw," "The Katydid," "Driving," "Today," "Moorings," "Wife-Swapping," "Hibernia," "Phases," "The Nightworker," "Six Road Ends," "Story County," "Gateposts," "The Retired Couple," "Chemical Street," "The Forties," "Zero-G," "The Strike," "The Nature Reserve," "Succession," "Underground," "A Tent," "The Country Cat," "Makings," "Since the Drowning," and "Energy"] (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - The Maiden Aunt [includes "Shoe Boxes," "Faith," "My Mother," "Spring," "Paying," "The 'Singer,'" "Poison," "Inch," "November," "Purgatory," "Work," "Coastline," "Arranmore," "The Folk Museum," "The Quilt," "The Presence," "Lent," "The Accident," "After the Weekend," "Subterfuge," "Cleaners," "Shifting Flats," "Prudence," "Maiden Aunt," "Buses," "The Hunter," "Coins," "The Fire-Dance," "Smoke," "June," "Honeymoon," "Wedlock," "Family Planning," "The Night-Mirror," "The House," "The Washeteria," "Driving," "Moorings," "Winter," and "Collusion"] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - The Marzipan Room [includes "Garam Masala," "Saint Sophia," "Today," "That Year," "Cicely," "Lychees," "The Moonbow," "The Roofspace," "Friday," "Chopping," "The Show House," "Gateposts," "The Love Game," "Those People," "Kells," "Waterford," "The Cure," "The Foundling Hospital," "Donegal," "The Black Nun," "The Thorough Bed," "Up the River," "Truganini," "The Half-Word," "The Katydid," "Vintage," "Chinoserie," "Tables," "The Cup," "The Kingfisher," "The Glory-Hole," "Dining Out," "Roulette," "The Rose Pirate," "Thinking Long," "The Grand Mountain Hotel," "The Shelter," "Curtains," "The Lavender Lady," and "The Dark Room"] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Uncollected Individual Poems [See also Subseries 2.5, Notebooks]
    - "About Girls," MS (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "The Accident," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "Adonis Dark," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "After a Dance," MS (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "After Moortown," MS and TS [variant titles: "After Reading Ted Hughes," "Moortown"] (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "After the Fire," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Aunts," TS] (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - "After the Weekend," TS (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - "Aldebaran," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - "Amelia," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Sofa," TS] (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - "Anna's Lane," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Children of the Mist," MS] (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - "April," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - "Aquarelle," [See Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "View Without a Room," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Aquascape," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Fossils," TS] (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - "Arranmore," TS [See also Subseries 1.1, Correspondence, 27 August 1975, MS] (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "As Leaves on Leaves," MS (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - "At the Gaeltacht," MS (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - "Aunt Dorothy's Tale," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Moonshots," MS] (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - "Bachelor's Walk," MS (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - "The Ballybogy Road," MS (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - "The [Bars] of Joseph," MS (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - "Birdwings," TS (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - "Birds, Women, and Writing," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "La Rosa de Santa Rosa," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Blackcurrants," MS (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - "The Black Nun," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Saint Sophia"] (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - "Block Magnificent," MS (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - "The Boathouse," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Children of the Mist," proof] (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - "The Bone-setter," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Confinement," TS] (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - "The Bouquet," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - "Bracelets," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "To My Grandmother," TS] (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - "Breaking Out," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems: "April," MS] (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - "Broca's Area," MS (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - "Broderie Anglaise," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - "The Buried Birds," MS (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - "Buses," TS [variant title: "Pets"] (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - "By the Sea," TS (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - "Cahal's Voice (On the Impossibility of Being Made Love To in Irish)," proof [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Plague Song," MS, TS, and proof] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Celiocanthe," MS (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - "A Change of Place," TS (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - "The Charm School," TS (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - "Chemical Street," TS (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - "The Child Bride," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Sunbench," TS] (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - "The Child of Loyalty," MS (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - "Chinoserie," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Katydid," MS] (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - "Choice," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "The Music Centre," MS] (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - "Choosing," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Ringleaders," MS] (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - "Christmas Clouds," MS (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - "The Christmas Police," MS (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - "Cicely," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Problem Girl," MS] (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - "Cishenden Ferns," MS (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - "Cleaners," TS [variant title: "Cleaning Women"] (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - "A Clockwise Journey," MS (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - "Clover," MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "At the Gaeltacht," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Coastline," TS (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - "Codes," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "April," MS] (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - "Coins," TS (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - "Collusion," TS (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - "Cologne," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Lucina," TS] (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - "The Coming of the God," TS (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - "Conch," MS (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - "Corporeal Ariel," MS (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - "The Country Cat," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Ducks and Drakes," MS] (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - "The Cup," TS (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - "Cupboard with Painted Ship," TS (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - "The Cure," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - "Dancing," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "The Music Centre," MS] (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - "The Dark Room," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Admiring the Furs," MS] (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - "The Daughter of the Air," MS (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - "Déjà Vu," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Black Nun," MS] (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - "Desh -- the Homeland," MS (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - "The Dial Painter," TS (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - "Dining Out," TS (Box 22, Folder 70)
    - "Dirge," MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "After a Dance," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Disappearance of Venus," TS (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - "The Dolphin," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - "Donegal," MS and TS (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - "The Door," TS (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - "A Dream of Rain," TS [variant title: "Energy"] [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Problems," MS] (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - "Drinking Song," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Driving," TS (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "Emily," TS (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "Enniscorthy," MS (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "Eskimos," TS [variant title: "June"] (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "Etiquette," TS (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "Evening Gold," MS (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "The Explanation," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "Family Planning," TS (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "The Fashion Parade," TS (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Fathering," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Aphrodisiac," TS] (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "Father's Day," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Aphrodisiac," TS] (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "The Feastday of Peace," Proof [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Plague Song," MS, TS, and proof] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Fire-Dance," TS (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "The Fire Tower," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - "First Sleep," TS (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - "Fishing," TS (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - "The Folk Museum," MS (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - "The Forgetting Door," MS (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - "The Forties," TS (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - "The Foundling Hospital," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Cure," MS] (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - "Friday," TS (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - "A Friend," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Door," TS] (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - "Garam Masala," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Curtains," MS] (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - "Garbo at the Gaumont," MS (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - "The Garden Gnome," TS (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - "Genesis," MS (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - "The Ginger Jar," MS (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - "The Girl Who Turned into a Sunflower," MS (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - "Girl-Mother and Child," TS (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - "The Glory Hole," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Curtains," MS] (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - "Goya," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - "Graceland," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Fire Tower," MS] (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - "The Grand Mountain Hotel," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Problem Girl," MS] (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - "The Grande Semaine," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, On Ballycastle Beach, "For a Young Matron," MS] (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - "The Grayling," TS (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - "The Greenhouse," TS [variant title: "Corals"] [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Etiquette," TS] (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - "The Half-Word," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Cup," TS] (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - "Hands," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - "Head of a Woman," proof [See Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Mrs. Orchard," MS and proof] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Healing Room," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - "Hendrix," MS (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - "Hibernia," TS (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - "Honeymoon," TS (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - "The Horse Fair," MS (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - "The House," MS and TS [variant title: "House"] (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - "Housemaid's Knee," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Sunbench," TS, and Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Child-Bride," MS] (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - "The Hunter," TS (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - "In Praise of Water," MS (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - "In the Day Room," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - "Inch," TS (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - "The Inferno Machine," TS (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - "Jazzmen Say Head," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - "The Josephine Look," MS (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - "Journey with S," MS (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - "Kells," TS (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - "The Key of B-Natural," MS (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - "The Kingfisher," TS (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - "The Landing, 1968," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Rain, "Harvest," MS] (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - "The Last War," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "The Music Centre," MS] (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - "Laurentia," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - "The Lavender Lady," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - "The Least Landscape," MS (Box 23, Folder 61)
    - "The Lemon Shed," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Adonis Dark," MS] (Box 23, Folder 62)
    - "Lent," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 63)
    - "Letter 'O,'" MS (Box 23, Folder 64)
    - "A Little Transfer," MS (Box 23, Folder 65)
    - "Living Beyond a Window," MS (Box 23, Folder 66)
    - "Lookout," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "April," MS] (Box 23, Folder 67)
    - "Lorea," MS (Box 23, Folder 68)
    - "The Love Game," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Problem Girl," MS] (Box 23, Folder 69)
    - "Maiden Aunt," TS (Box 23, Folder 70)
    - "Makings," MS (Box 23, Folder 71)
    - "Malahide," TS [variant title: "Malahide Castle"] [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Long Engagement," TS] (Box 23, Folder 72)
    - "Managed News," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "Orant Figure," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "March," TS (Box 23, Folder 73)
    - "Mariola with Angel Choir," MS (Box 23, Folder 74)
    - "Marriage," MS (Box 23, Folder 75)
    - "Martini Terrace," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 76)
    - "Mews," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Lavender Lady," MS] (Box 23, Folder 77)
    - "Mirror-Time," TS (Box 23, Folder 78)
    - "The Moon Mother," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Lucina," TS] (Box 23, Folder 79)
    - "The Moonbow," TS (Box 23, Folder 80)
    - "Moonlight," MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Evening Gold," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Moon-Shell," MS and TS (Box 23, Folder 81)
    - "Moorings," TS [variant title: "August"] (Box 23, Folder 82)
    - "The Moscow Trial," MS (Box 23, Folder 83)
    - "Moving Back," [See Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "To My Grandmother," TS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Moving Flats," TS [variant title: "Shifting Flats] (Box 23, Folder 84)
    - "The Mulberry Tree," MS (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "The Music Loft," TS (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "My Everyday Dream," [See Subseries 2.1:, Shelmalier, "The Temple of Janus," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Names," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Ducks and Drakes," MS, and Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Grayling," TS] (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Narcissus," MS (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "The Nature Reserve," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Problems," MS] (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "A New Biography," TS (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "The Night Mirror," TS [variant title: "Marie"] (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - "Night When One Hears the Sea Without Seeing It," MS (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - "The Nightworker," TS (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Nocturne" [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "More Than a Letter," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "November," TS (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - "Offspring," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - "On a March Morning," TS [See also Subseries 2.3, Translations by McGuckian, Ní Dhomhnaill, Nuala, "Night Fishing," MS] (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - "On the New Portrait of Seamus Heaney, by -- --, in the Naughton Gallery," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "Orant Figure," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "On Waking Up After the Birth of a First Baby [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Fathering," TS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Orange Island," Proof [See Subseries 2.1, Shelmalier, "Plague Song," MS, TS, and proof] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Painting a Verb," MS (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - "Paperweight," TS (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - "Part Two Aquarelle," MS (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - "Pemmican," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Magazines," MS] (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - "A Perrier Day-For My Horse 'Daylight,'" MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - "Petite Maison," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - "Phantasmagoria," TS (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - "Phases," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Ringleaders," MS] (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - "Poem for a Lost Birthday," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Two Women, Two Shores, "Children of the Mist," MS, and "The Missing Tennis Suit," MS] (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - "Poem For Thanksgiving," MS (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "Poetry Days," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - "Poison," TS (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - "Postlude," MS (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - "The Press," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Dining Out," TS] (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - "Prudence," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Moving Flats," TS] (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - "Purgatory," TS (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - "The Purification," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Perfect Mother," TS] (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - "Queen Maeve Bridge," MS (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - "The Quilt," TS (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - "Rainer Maria Rilke," MS (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - "The Rainshadow," MS (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - "Reaper," TS (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - "A Reset Year," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - "The Rising Sea," [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Makings," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Robin," TS (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - "Romans," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Dolphin," MS] (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - "The Roofspace," TS (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - "Room Twenty-Seven," MS [variant title: "Room Twenty-Five"] (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - "Roulette," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Katydid," MS] (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - "The Sands of Saint Cyprian," MS [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "The Gorgon as Mistress of the Animals," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Santo Spirito," TS (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - "Saskatoon, Saskatchewan," TS (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - "The Sea-Clock," MS (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - "The Sea-House," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Dolphin," MS and TS] (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - "The Sea-Wood," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Music Loft," MS] (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - "The Second Wife," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, Venus and the Sea, "Star," MS] (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - "The Sent Back Gift/Present," MS (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - "The Serviettes," [See Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Long Engagement," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Shelter," TS (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - "The Ship-Christener," MS (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - "Shoe Boxes," MS (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - "Shot Angel," MS [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Mariola with Angel Choir," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Show House," TS (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - "Shrovetide," MS (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - "The Signal," MS (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - "Signs," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "Distance," TS] (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - "The Silver Marsh," TS (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - "Since the Drowning," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Makings," MS] (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - "Six Road Ends," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - "Skirt of a Thousand Triangles," MS (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - "The Sky" [See Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Hendrix," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Sleep-Out," MS [variant title: "The Water Tower"] (Box 24, Folder 59)
    - "The Snow Poem," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Heiress," MS] (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - "The Snowflake Album," MS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "Mariola with Angel Choir," MS] (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - "Snuff," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 62)
    - "So Farewell, Rome," MS (Box 24, Folder 63)
    - "Solstice," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Portrait of Joanna, "Ringleaders," MS] (Box 24, Folder 64)
    - "The Space Composer," [See Subseries 2.1, Marconi's Cottage, "Charlotte's Delivery," MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Spring-Loss," MS (Box 24, Folder 65)
    - "Spy Fever-For John's Birthday," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 66)
    - "The Statue," [See also Subseries 2.1, The Flower Master and Other Poems, "The Standing," TS] (Box 24, Folder 67)
    - "The Stone-Hitter," MS and TS (Box 24, Folder 68)
    - "The Stone-word," proof [See Subseries 2.1, The Currach Requires No Harbours, "Bright Star, I Say that Thou art Dust," proof] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Story County," TS [See also Subseries 2.1, Uncollected Individual Poems, "The Fire Tower," MS] (Box 24, Folder 69)
    - "The Strike," TS (Box 24, Folder 70)